# **Dongho Kang**

Wasserwerkstrasse 12, Zurich 8006, Switzerland kangd@ethz.ch • +41 78 677 90 49 • https://donghok.me/

# RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research aims to create a legged robot that can perform natural, animal-like motion. Thus, my research interests are broad ranging to legged locomotion control, computational model of character animation and design optimization for robotics applications.

#### **EDUCATION**

### ETH Zürich, Zurich, Switzerland

Doctoral Student in Computer Science

Apr 2020 - Present

• Advisor: Prof. Dr. Stelian Coros

M.Sc. ETH in Mechanical Engineering

Sep 2016 - Aug 2019

• Advisor: Prof. Dr. Marco Hutter

· Graduated with distiction

### Seoul National University, Seoul, South Korea

■ B.Sc. in Mechanical Engineering and B.Sc. in Computer Science

Mar 2009 – Aug 2016

• Advisor: Prof. Dr. Dongjun Lee

· Graduated with honor (Cum Laude)

# RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

### Computational Robotics Lab, ETH Zürich

Scientific Assistant

Dec 2019 – Present

• Supervisors: Prof. Dr. Stelian Coros

• Aim to build bio-inspired quadrupedal robots that perform more natural and animal-like motion.

### Robotic Systems Lab, ETH Zürich

Master's Student

Sep 2017 – Nov 2019

• Supervisors: David Höller, Dr. Jemin Hwangbo and Prof. Dr. Marco Hutter

Conducted the research on learning-based collision avoidance for a legged robot ANYmal.

• Participated in the development of RaiSim: a physics engine for robotics and AI research.

#### **Interactive & Networked Robotics Lab**, Seoul National University

Undergraduate Research Assistant

Sep 2014 – Jan 2016

• Supervisors: Prof. Dr. Dongjun Lee

· Participated in the research on state estimation and control strategy for multi-robot cooperative systems

### PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS & ACTIVITIES

### NVIDIA, Zurich, Switzerland

Deep Learning Intern

Jun 2018 – Dec 2018

· Projects: Super-Resolution and Anti-aliasing methods based on deep learning.

### LeisureQ Inc., Seoul, South Korea

Web Developer Intern

Jan 2016 – Sep 2016

Projects: Backend web application for E-commerce website Gajago: http://www.thegajago.com

### **CNP Technology Inc.**, Seoul, South Korea

Hardware and CAD Engineer

Jan 2016 – Sep 2016

### **PUBLICATIONS**

### CONFERENCES

- [1] Dongho Kang, Flavio De Vincenti, Naomi C. Adam, and Stelian Coros, "Animal Motions on Legged Robots Using Nonlinear Model Predictive Control," in *International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)*, Oct 2022 (accepted).
- [2] Dongho Kang, Simon Zimmermann, and Stelian Coros, "Animal Gaits on Quadrupedal Robots using Motion Matching and Model-Based Control," in *International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)*, Sep 2021.
- [3] Flavio De Vincenti, <u>Dongho Kang</u>, and Stelian Coros, "Control-Aware Design Optimization for Bio-Inspired Quadruped Robots," in *International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)*, Sep 2021.

[4] Changu Kim, Hyunsoo Yang, <u>Dongho Kang</u> and Dongjun Lee, "2-D Cooperative Localization with Omni-Directional Mobile Robots," in *International Conference on Ubiquitous Robots and Ambient Intelligence*, Goyang, South Korea, Oct 2015.

#### WORKSHOP

[1] Dongho Kang, Flavio De Vincenti, and Stelian Coros, "Nonlinear Model Predictive Control for Quadrupedal Locomotion Using Second-Order Sensitivity Analysis," in *ICRA 2022: 6th Full-Day Workshop on Legged Robots*, May 2022.

#### **THESIS**

[1] <u>Dongho Kang</u>, "End-to-End Collision Avoidance from Depth Input with Memory-based Deep RL," <u>Master's thesis</u>, the Department of Mechanical and Process Engineering, ETH Zürich, Aug 2019.

### .....

INVITED TALK

<ul> <li>Robot Intelligence Lab, Korea University, Seoul, South Korea</li> </ul>	Apr 2021
<ul> <li>NAVER LABS Corp., Seoul, South Korea</li> </ul>	Dec 2019

■ Max Planck ETH Center for Learning Systems Symposium, Tübingen, Germany Feb 2019

## AWARDS & SCHOLARSHIPS

Birkigt Scholarship, ETH Zürich
 Stipendiary scholarship for international master student.

Eminence Scholarship, Seoul National University
 Full-tuition scholarship for one academic semester for outstanding academic performance.

Merit-based Scholarship, Seoul National University
 Half-tuition scholarship for one academic semester for outstanding academic performance.

Development Fund Scholarship, Seoul National University
 Full-tuition scholarship for one academic year for outstanding academic performance.

# TEACHING EXPERIENCE

### ETH Zürich, Zurich, Switzerland

<ul><li>Teaching Assistant, Computational Models of Motion (Spring)</li></ul>	2021 - 2022
■ Teaching Assistant, Visual Computing (Autumn)	2020 - 2022

### Seoul National University, Seoul, South Korea

<ul> <li>Mentor, SNU Samsung Convergence Software Course Program</li> </ul>	Jan 2015 – Dec 2015
■ Teaching Assistant, MAE 446.204A: Dynamics	Jan 2014 – Dec 2014
■ Teaching Assistant, PA 034.013: Basic Physics 2	Sep 2011 – Dec 2011

### LANGUAGES

- Korean: Native language.
- English: Fluent.

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

### **Programming and Software**

C/C++, C#, Python, Matlab/Octave, Unix/Linux, Tensorflow, Pytorch, ROS, Open Dynamics Engine, Unity

### **Experience with Robots**

UnitreeRobotics Aliengo, A1, Go1, ANYbotics ANYmal,

#### REFERENCES

#### Prof. Dr. Stelian Coros

Associate Professor in the Department of Computer Science ETH Zürich Stampfenbachstrasse 48 (Sumatrastrasse 11), 8092, Zurich, Switzerland scoros@inf.ethz.ch • +41 44 632 02 15

### ■ Prof. Dr. Marco Hutter

Associate Professor in the Department of Mechanical and Process Engineering ETH Zürich

Leonhardstrasse 21, 8092 Zurich, Switzerland mahutter@ethz.ch • +41 44 632 74 17

### ■ Prof. Dr. Jemin Hwangbo

Assistant Professor in the Department of Mechanical Engineering Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology jhwangbo@kaist.ac.kr

### ■ Prof. Dr. Dongjun Lee

Professor in the Department of Mechanical Engineering Seoul National University 1 Gwanak-Ro, Gwanak-Gu, Seoul, 08826, South Korea djlee@snu.ac.kr • +82 2 880 1724